Contact

9843623018 (Mobile) shresthasurendra37@gmail.co m

www.linkedin.com/in/surendra37 (LinkedIn) surendra37.com.np (Portfolio)

Top Skills

.NET Core

.NET Framework

Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF)

Surendra Shrestha

Software engineer at Asteroid Venture Nepal

Summary

** result-oriented **| **3.5+ years of experience** | **C#** | **.NET Framework** | **.NET Core** | **WPF** | **Windows Forms** | ** SQL Databases** | ** MVVM** | ** LINQ ** | **Scrapy** | **Docker**

I am a result-oriented developer since 2017 with a lot of professional experience in Windows desktop software development. For the last years, my preferred technologies are C#/.NET/.NET CORE, WPF, MVVM, Entity Framework, and MS SQL Server. I always use the latest technologies and best practices, so you can be sure that you will get the highest possible quality. Client satisfaction is the most important for me.

Over the year of working, I have gained expertise that covers:

- ✓ Architecting your next enterprise level software solution
- ✓ Programming anything from your imagination to a solution.
- ✓ Web Development
- ✓ Desktop Application Development
- ✓ Database Development
- ✓ Debugging and maintenance of existing desktop applications
- ✓ Web scraping

My technical skillset includes:

- ✓ C# ✓ .NET Framework ✓ .NET CORE
- ✓ ASP.NET (WebForms, MVC, Core)
- ✓ WPF ✓ Windows Forms ✓ MVVM ✓ Material Design UI
- ✓ Microsoft SQL Server ✓ MySQL ✓ SQLite
- ✓ MS Sharepoint
- √ Scrapy
- ✓ Docker

I am hard working, focused and effective team player. I have high motivation, extensive knowledge, good logical and problem solving skills.

I am here to help you and bring your projects to life! Regards, Surendra

Experience

Asteroid Venture (AV)

Software Engineer

December 2018 - Present (1 year 11 months)

- # Started working on Enterprise Content Management (ECM) Migration Software.
- # Worked on migration of data from different ECM system to Microsoft's Sharepoint.
- # Worked on Window's Communication Foundation (WCF) system and SQLite/SQLCe databases.
- # Worked as a Window's Presentation Framework (WPF) developer for analyzer tools.
- # Consuming SOAP and REST API
- # .NET Core

DOTMARK SOLUTIONS LTD

.NET Developer

December 2017 - December 2018 (1 year 1 month)

Nepal

- # Started Programming career as a .NET Software programmer.
- # Got involved on Desktop application for health/hospital management system.
- # Worked on Windows Presentation Framework (WPF).
- # Used Microsoft's 'Prism Framework' for MVVM (Model View ViewModel) implementation.
- # Worked in NodeJS using Express Framework for API development.

Institute of Engineering Thapathali Campus Student

January 2014 - December 2017 (4 years)

Nepal

Joined Bachelor in Engineering in Electronics and Communication Engineering

- # Developed 'Beam Analysis' Software as Minor project, to calculate shear force and bending moments at different point using Microsoft's Window's Form Application.
- # Participated in different boot camp programs organized by NCELL, Microsoft, etc.
- # Created 'Speaker Recognition System' as Major Project, using Python as a programming language using Mel-Frequency Cepstrum Co-efficient (MFCC) to recognize the User based on their audio input.

Robotics and Automation Center, Thapathali Campus Hardware Programmer 2014 - 2017 (3 years) Nepal

- # Joined Robotics and Automation Center
- # Worked on a team to create simple task completing robots and program it to perform those tasks using C programming language.
- # Participated in International Robotics Competition (IRC) held in Mumbai, India for two times.

Education

Institute of Engineering Thapathali Campus
Bachelor of Engineering - BE, Electronics and Communications
Engineering · (2014 - 2018)

Reliance International Academy
Intermediate Science, Computer Science · (2011 - 2013)